Guide to the Horace Walpole Collection
The Lewis Walpole Library
Horace Walpole collection
1725-1797
LWL MSS 1
The Lewis Walpole Library
17
44 boxes
The collection includes approximately 3,000 letters to and from Horace Walpole as well as other manuscript materials by him, including copies of Aedes Walpolianae and The Mysterious Mother, his commonplace books, his "Books of Materials," and various miscellanies.
Walpole, Horace, 1717-1797
Accruals
The bulk of the collection was assembled by Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis from 1929 until his death in 1979. The library continues to add to the collection as materials become available.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes approximately 3,000 letters to and from Horace Walpole as well as other manuscript materials by him, including copies of Aedes Walpolianae and The Mysterious Mother, his commonplace books, "Books of Materials," and various miscellanies.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Horace Walpole's Correspondence. II. Horace Walpole's Manuscripts. III. Manuscripts transcribed or annotated by Horace Walpole.
Biographical / Historical
Horace Walpole (1717-1797) was an author, politician, antiquarian, patron of the arts, and prolific letter writer. He was the youngest son of Sir Robert Walpole, England's first prime minister, and moved in a circle comprised of the most influential figures in both the social and political worlds of 18th-century England. He wrote histories, fiction, plays, verse, essays, political pieces, and art catalogues, and compiled notebooks covering topics such as "Anecdotes of Painting in England," "The Catalogue of Engravers who have been born, or resided in England," "Catalogue of the Royal and Noble Authors of England, Scotland, and Ireland," and "Essay on Modern Gardening." Walpole was the author of Historic Doubts on the Life and Reign of King Richard the Third and Memoirs of the Last Ten Years of the Reign of George II. His fiction included the first gothic novel, The Castle of Otranto; the fantasy Hieroglyphic Tales; the play "Mysterious Mother"; and Fugitive Pieces in Verse and Prose.
Walpole founded the Strawberry Hill Press, which published Thomas Gray's Odes, at his gothic revival home Strawberry Hill, in Twickenham. He spent the better part of his long life building a significant collection of art and objects which he displayed at Strawberry Hill, and extensively documented in two editions of his self-published catalogue A Description of the Villa of Mr. Horace Walpole.
Existence and Location of Copies
Most of the correspondence in this collection has been published in The Yale Edition of Horace Walpole's Correspondence (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1937-1983). An electronic version was made available in 2011. See: http://images.library.yale.edu/hwcorrespondence/
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
From the bequest of W. S. Lewis and Annie Burr Lewis, with subsequent additions by purchase.
France -- Social life and customs -- 18th century; Great Britain -- History -- George II, 1727-1760; Great Britain -- History -- George III, 1760-1820; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 18th century; Great Britain -- Intellectual life -- 18th century; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 18th century; Great Britain -- History -- 18th century; Art -- Collectors and collecting -- Great Britain; Authors, English -- 18th century; Authors, French -- 18th century; Clergy -- Great Britain; Courts and courtiers -- England; Nobility -- Great Britain; Legislators -- Great Britain; Poets, English -- 18th century; Correspondence; Poetry; Walpole, Horace, 1717-1797; Walpole, Robert, Earl of Orford, 1676-1745; Walpole family; Ashton, Thomas, 1716-1775; Berry, Agnes, 1764-1852; Berry, Mary, 1763-1852; Chute, John, 1701-1776; Cole, William, 1714-1782; Conway, Henry Seymour, 1721-1795; Dalrymple, David, Sir, 1726-1792; Du Deffand, Marie de Vichy Chamrond, marquise, 1697-1780; Chatterton, Thomas, 1752-1770; Gray, Thomas, 1716-1771; Hertford, Francis Ingram Seymour, Marquis of, 1743-1822; Mason, William, 1725-1797; Montagu, George, ca. 1713-1780; More, Hannah, 1745-1833; Selwyn, George Augustus, 1719-1791; Seton, Barbara Cecilia; Upper Ossory, Anne Liddell Fitzpatrick, Countess of, -1804; West, Richard, 1716-1742; Wiart, Jean François; Strawberry Hill (Twickenham, London, England); Lewis, W. S. (Wilmarth Sheldon), 1895-1979
- Horace Walpole's Correspondence, 1725-1797; Series I; 12
  Arrangement
  Correspondence is arranged in subseries, one for each of Horace Walpole's correspondents. Within each subseries correspondence is arranged chronologically with letters to and from Horace Walpole interfiled. Undated letters are filed at the end.
  OS ("old style") and NS ("new style"). Letters preceding the change of calendar in 1752 are arranged in the sequence in which they were actually written, allowing eleven days' difference between "new style" letters from the Continent, and "old style" letters from England.
  General
  Citations to copies in the two standard editions -- Toynbee and the Yale Edition -- are provided where appropriate. See Bibliography in Adminstrative Information for complete citation to these works.
  - Adam, Robert
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, Circa 1766 Sep 26 (Box 1, Folder 1a)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 8. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 11-12.
  - Aiguillon, (dowager) Duchesse d', Aiguillon, Anne-Charlotte de Crussol de Florensac, duchesse d, 1700-1772
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, Circa 1766 Mar 9 (Box 1, Folder 1b)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 8. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (Extract in an unknown hand), 1766 Nov 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (Extract in Jean-François Wiart's hand), 1766 Nov 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      See note in Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 45.
  - Ailesbury, Countess of *
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1751 Nov 3 OS (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 316-17. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, Circa 1752 Feb 15 OS (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 325-27. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1752 Jun 9 OS (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 337-38. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, Circa 1753 Mar 25 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 351. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, Circa 1755 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 395-96. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1756 Jan 31 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 433-35. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1756 Jun 15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 465-66. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1756 Oct 21 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 476-78. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1757 Jun 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 484-85. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1757 Jul 7 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 492. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1757 Sep 16 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 504-5. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1757 Oct 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 509-10. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1757 Oct 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 510-11. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1757 Oct 7 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 511. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, [1758 Mar 24 or 31?] (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Yale Edition, v. 37, p. 525. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1760 Aug 23 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Yale Edition, v. 38, p. 70-72. Toynbee iv, p. 417-19 and Supp. ii, p. 117.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1761 Jun 13 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Yale Edition, v. 38, p. 87-91. Toynbee v, p. 65-68 and Supp. ii, p. 119.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1761 Jul 20 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Yale Edition, v. 38, p. 99-103. Toynbee v, p. 80-83 and Supp. ii, p. 120.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1761 Sep 27 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Yale Edition, v. 38, p. 124-29. Toynbee v, p. 117-21 and Supp. ii, p. 122-23.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1761 Oct 10 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Yale Edition, v. 38, p. 130-33. Toynbee v, p. 130-33 and Supp. ii, p. 123.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1761 Nov 28 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Yale Edition, v. 38, p. 142-45. Toynbee v, p. 145-47 and Supp. ii, p. 123-24.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1762 Mar 15 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Yale Edition, v. 38, p. 153-56. Toynbee v, p. 184-85 and Supp. ii, p. 125.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1762 Jul 31 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Yale Edition, v. 38, p. 163-65. Toynbee v, p. 221-22.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1772 Dec 29 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 166-69. Toynbee viii, p. 221-23 and Supp. ii, p. 142-43.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1774 Nov 7 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 206-9. Toynbee ix, p. 81-84 and Supp. ii, p. 144-46.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1774 Nov 23 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 216-19. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 237-41.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1775 Aug 17 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 253-54. Toynbee ix, p. 234-35 and Supp. ii, p. 147.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1775 Aug 20 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 255-56. Toynbee ix, p. 236-37 and Supp. ii, p. 147.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1775 Dec 12 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 272-73. Toynbee ix, p. 294 and Supp. ii, p. 148.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1776 Aug 22 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 282-83. Toynbee Supp. ii, p. 151-52.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1778 Jun 25 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 299-300. Toynbee x, p. 267-68 and Supp. ii, p. 158-59.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1779 Jul 10 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 331-34. Toynbee x, p. 446-48 and Supp. ii, p. 160-61.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1779 Jul 23 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 335-37. Toynbee x, p. 453-55.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1779 Oct 28 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 341-42. Toynbee Supp. i, p. 276-78.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1781 Jan 21 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 364-66. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1784 Jun 8 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 413-15. Toynbee xiii, p. 158-59 and Supp. ii, p. 166.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1793 [Sep?] (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 499-501. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 307-8.
  - Albani, Alessandro, Cardinal
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1740 Jul 3 NS (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 29-30. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 107-8.
  - Alderson, Rev. Christopher
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1783 Jun 1 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 54-55. Not in Toynbee.
  - Alison, Mrs.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1790 Jan 16 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 264-65. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1790 Feb 18 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 272-75. Not in Toynbee.
  - Allan, George
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1776 Dec 9 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 350-51. Toynbee ix, p. 447.
  - Amelia, Princess
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (Copy in Horace Walpole's hand), 1786 Apr 2 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      See note in Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 160.
  - Ashton, Rev. Thomas *
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1740 May 14 NS (Box 1, Folder 47)
      Yale Edition, v. 13, p. 214-18. Toynbee i, p. 64.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1741 Jul 25 OS (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Yale Edition, v. 13, p. 246-47. Not in Toynbee.
  - Astle, Thomas *
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1768 Jan 16 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 119-20. Toynbee vii, p. 155.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1768 Apr 22 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 144. Toynbee vii, p. 184.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1785 Jul 19 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 145-46. Toynbee xiii, p. 295.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1785 Aug 5 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 147-48. Toynbee xiii, p. 303.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1788 Jul 29 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 223. Toynbee xiv, p. 64.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1790 Jan 30 (Box 1, Folder 53a)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 266. Toynbee xiv, p. 246.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (Copy in an unknown hand), 1790 Jan 30 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      See note in Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 266.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1790 Apr 30 (Box 1, Folder 55)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 279-80. Toynbee xiv, p. 250.
  - Bauffremont, Prince de
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1780 Aug 5 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 415-16. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 257-58.
  - Baynes, John
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1782 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 10-11. Toynbee xii, p. 255.
  - Beauchamp, Francis Seymour Conway, Viscount *
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1762 Mar 13 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Yale Edition, v. 38, p. 152-53.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1772 Mar 24 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 155-56.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1788 Jul 13 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Yale Edition, v. 39, p. 461-63.
  - Beauclerk, Lady Diana *
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1775 [Dec 16?] (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 321-22. Not in Toynbee.
      Verses by Horace Walpole about Henry Dundas on verso.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, [Between 1782 and 1790] (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 450-51. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (Copy in Thomas Kirgate's hand), 1793 Dec 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 397-98. Toynbee Supp. ii, p. 68-69.
  - Beauclerk, Hon. Topham *
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1775 Aug 19 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 308-10. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 242-43.
  - Beauvau, Prince de
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1740 Oct 19 NS (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 30-32. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 108-9.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1776 Jan 27 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 330-32. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1777 Mar 29 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 357-58. Not in Toynbee.
  - Bedford, Charles
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1787 Aug 9 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 198. Toynbee Supp. ii, p. 19-20.
  - Bedford, Gertrude, Duchess of
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, No date (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 452. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 312.
  - Bedford, Grosvenor
    Related material:
    Document appointing Bedford as his deputy usher of the Exchequer dated 1755 August 21 is shelved as: LWL MSS 1 Box 2 Folder 14H (Drawer).
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1743 Aug 29 OS (Box 2, Folder 14a)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 41. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1755 Oct 16 (Box 2, Folder 14b)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 86. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1756 Jun 24 (Box 2, Folder 14c)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 86-87. Toynbee Supp. i, p. 71-72.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1758 Aug 29 (Box 2, Folder 14d)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 142. Toynbee iv, p. 180.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, Circa 1761 Jul 18 (Box 2, Folder 14e)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 203. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1761 Sep 23 (Box 2, Folder 14f)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 206. Toynbee v, p. 109-10.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1765 Sep 5 (Box 2, Folder 14g)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 380-81. Toynbee vi, p. 290-91.
  - Beloe, Rev. William *
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1792 Aug 5 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 215-17. Toynbee xv, p. 452 and Supp. ii, p. 55-56.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1792 Nov 2 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 226-29.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1794 Oct 19 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 254-55.
  - Berry, Mary *
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1788 Oct 14 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Yale Edition, v. 11, p. 1. Toynbee xiv, p. 90.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole (Copy in Mary Berry's hand of verse only), 1789 Dec (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1791 Aug 31- Sep 1 (Box 2, Folder 19a)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Purchased from Bonhams, lot 174, 18 June 2014.
  - Bindley, James
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (Copy in an unknown hand), 1781 Sep 7 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 440-41. Toynbee i, p. 281.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 9 Nov 1776 (Box 2, Folder 20a)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 350.
  - Birch, Rev. Thomas
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1764 Aug 30 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 356-57. Not in Toynbee.
  - Boufflers, Marie-Charlotte-Hippolyte, Comtesse de
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1766 Feb 6 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 2. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 194.
  - Bowle, Rev. John *
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1764 Feb 6 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 296-99. Not in Toynbee.
  - Brown, Margaret (Cecil), Lady
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1756 Nov 28 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 89-90. Toynbee Supp. iii, p. 141-42.
  - Browne, Frances (Sheldon), Lady *
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, [Circa 1772 Nov 1?] (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 170-71.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1778 Oct 28 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 188-90.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (in Thomas Kirgate's hand), 1778 Nov 5 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 190-92.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (in Thomas Kirgate's hand), 1778 Dec 18 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 192-95.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1779 Aug 23 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 196.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1779 Aug-Sep bis (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 197.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, [Circa 1779 Sep-Oct?] (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 198.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1780 Sep 15 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 198-99.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, Circa 1781 Jul 18 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 202.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, Circa 1781 Jul 19 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 202-3.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, Circa 1781 Oct 1 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 203.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1783 Jul 23 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 204.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, [1783 Sep or Oct?] (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (in Thomas Kirgate's hand), [1783 Sep or Oct?] bis (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 205.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1783 Oct 17 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 209-10.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1784 Sep 16 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 217-18.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1785 Aug 23 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 235-36.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (in Thomas Kirgate's hand), 1785 Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 237-39.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1788 Sep 27 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 286-89.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole ("If your Ladyship goes ..."), No date (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 405-6.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole ("If your Ladyship is ..."), No date (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 406.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole ("Pray, my dear Madam ..."), No date (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Letter from Horace Walpole ("I do not go ..."), No date (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 407.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole ("I am exceedingly ..."), No date (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 408.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole ("I am much obliged ..."), No date (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Letter from Horace Walpole ("Will your Ladyship ..."), No date (Box 2, Folder 50)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 409.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole ("I will beg ..."), No date (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Letter from Horace Walpole ("I forgot yesterday ..."), No date (Box 2, Folder 52)
      Yale Edition, v. 31, p. 410.
  - Buchan, 11th Earl of *
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1781 Feb 10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 150-51.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1781 Dec 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 156-59.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1782 Jul 27 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 162-63.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1782 Sep 15 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 163-65.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1783 May 12 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 178-82.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1785 Sep 23 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 185-88.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1787 Feb 11 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 193-94.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1788 Jan 29 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 343-44.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1792 Jan 23 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Yale Edition, v. 15, p. 213-14.
  - Buckinghamshire, 2d Earl of
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1746 Jun 21 NS (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Yale Edition, v. 40, p. 56-57. Not in Toynbee.
  - Bull, Richard *
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1780 Jul 7 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 414. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1781 Dec 20 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 467-68. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1789 Mar 30 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 237. Not in Toynbee.
  - Buller, Mrs
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1786 Apr 6 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 161-62. Not in Toynbee.
  - Bunbury, Henry William
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1781 Apr 28 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Yale Edition, v. 41, p. 429-30. Toynbee xi, p. 434-35.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1791 Mar 16 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 316-17. Toynbee Supp. ii, p. 50, n. 7.
  - Burke, Edmund
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1782 Jul 7 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 23. Not in Toynbee.
  - Burke, Richard
    - Letter to Horace Walpole, 1782 Jul 7 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 24-25. Not in Toynbee.
    - Horace Walpole's copy of Mr. Burke's proposal, 1782 Jul 7 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 25-27.
    - Horace Walpole's notes on the Burkes' proposal, 1782 Jul 7 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 27-28.
  - Burney, Dr Charles *
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1785 Sep 6 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 149. Toynbee xiii, p. 317.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1786 Jul 6 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 170-71. Toynbee xiii, p. 397.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole (Draft in Charles Burney's hand), 1786 Jul 20 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 171-73. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole, 1787 Dec 19 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 202. Toynbee Supp. ii, p. 20-21.
    - Letter to Horace Walpole (Draft in Charles Burney's hand), 1791 Jul 8 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 329-30. Not in Toynbee.
    - Letter from Horace Walpole (in Thomas Kirgate's hand), 1796 Feb 20 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Yale Edition, v. 42, p. 427. Toynbee Supp. ii, p. 73-74.